[ Music ]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name is Shiva Sundar, and I'm
我是 Shiva Sundar
extremely excited to talk about
非常高兴能和大家讨论
HEVC Video with Alpha.
有 Alpha 通道 的 HEVC 视频
You're probably familiar with
你也许很熟悉
Alpha channels in image files today.
图像文件中的 Alpha 通道
Alpha channels are ubiquitous
Alpha 通道在图像文件
in image files, in our apps and on
App 和网络中无处不在
When there's an Alpha channel
当图像文件中有 Alpha 通道时
in an image file, every pixel in the
图像中的每个像素
image gets opacity along with
都会得到不透明度及其颜色
This allows us to have an image
这使得我们
that has a complex,
可以得到一个复杂的
non-rectangular shape but looks
非矩形的图像
natural when composited against
但在许多不同的背景下
many different backgrounds.
合成时看起来很自然
So Alpha and transparency are
所以 Alpha 通道和透明度很常见
common and used all over the web
主要通过像 PNG 这样的
principally by still image
静止图像格式
formats like PNG.
在网络上使用
Alpha in video has been less
视频中的 Alpha
common.
不太常见
It has been a professional video
它是专业的
workflow tool.
视频工作流程工具
The formats used in professional
专业视频工作流
video workflows like Apple
如 Apple ProRes 4444 中
ProRes 4444 are very high data
使用的格式数据速率非常高
rate and not appropriate for
不适合传送
In 2017, Apple introduced
2017 年 Apple 推出了
support for the HEIF image file
对 HEIF 图像文件格式的支持
format, which lets us take
这使我们可以
advantage of the advanced
利用 HEVC 中的
lossy compression
高级有损压缩技术
technologies in HEVC to compress
来压缩静止图像
HEIF also lets you include an
HEIF 还允许在图像文件中
Alpha channel in image files.
包含 Alpha 通道
In fact, this year we are
事实上 今年我们增加了
sequences, which lets you have
对 HEIF 序列的支持
multiple images in a single
允许你在一个文件中
file.
拥有多个图像
HEIF sequences also support
HEIF 序列也支持
Alpha channels.
Alpha 通道
For some time we've recognized
一段时间以来
the need for a lower bitrate way
我们已经认识到
to include Alpha in motion
采用较低比特率的方式
video.
将 Alpha 包含在动态视频当中的需求
And so we said let's use that
所以我们说
advanced loosy compression
让我们来使用
technology to support Alpha
先进的有损压缩技术
channels in video files as well.
来支持视频文件中的 Alpha 通道
Playback of HEVC video with
在所有支持的设备和计算机上
Alpha is supported in iOS 13,
iOS 13 tvOS 13
tvOS 13 and macOS Catalina on
和 macOS Catalina
all supported devices and
都支持使用 Alpha
computers.
播放 HEVC 视频
Encoding is supported on all of
所有具有 HEVC 编码器的
those devices and computers that
设备和计算机
have an HEVC encoder.
都支持编码
Having a video with Alpha format
拥有 Alpha 格式的视频
that works well at bit rates low
效果很好
enough for distribution opens up
其比特率足够低可以分发
many opportunities.
这创造了许多机会
You can have rich,
你可以使用
non-rectangular motion video
丰富的非矩形动态视频内容
content that you incorporate as
作为 App
a layer as part of your app's
表达体验的一部分
It could be pre-rendered like an
它可以像动画一样
animation.
预先渲染
Such an element can move around
这样的元素
on top of a complicated
可以在复杂的背景上移动
background and you could even have
甚至有几个元素
several of them to give a
可以给人一种
feeling of depth or complex
深度或复杂交互的感觉
Because these are movies they
因为这些是视频
can have synchronized sound
它们可以有同步的音轨
tracks so the characters in
所以这样一来
these non-rectangular movies can
这些非矩形影片中的角色
talk.
就可以说话了
&gt;&gt; Highly professional.
&gt;&gt; 超级专业的
&gt;&gt; Alpha channel.
&gt;&gt; Alpha 通道
&gt;&gt; Content.
&gt;&gt; 内容
&gt;&gt; For you.
&gt;&gt; 为你而设
&gt;&gt; Woo-hoo.
&gt;&gt; Woo-hoo
&gt;&gt; They could be integrated into
&gt;&gt; 它们可以将
games using SpriteKit, SceneKit
SpriteKit SceneKit
or Metal.
或 Metal 集成到游戏当中
In this context, we have
在本文中
provided you with some sample
我们向你提供了一些示例代码
code on how to record a SceneKit
介绍了如何用 Alpha 通道
scene into a HEVC video with
将 SceneKit 场景录制到 HEVC 视频中
Alpha and how to render another
以及如何在 SpriteKit 场景
in a SpriteKit scene.
中渲染另一个场景
On web pages, they could bring
在网页上
interactive elements to life.
它们可使互动元素活跃起来
HEVC video with Alpha is
iOS 13 和 macOS Catalina 中的
supported by Safari in iOS 13
Safari 支持带有
and macOS Catalina.
Alpha 的 HEVC 视频
Safari can also tell the web
Safari 还可以告诉网页
page whether this feature is
是否支持此功能
For more information on using
想要获得有关 API 媒体功能的
the media capabilities API, be
更多使用信息
sure to check out the What's New
请务必查看这个视频
in Authentication, Safari and
《What's New in Authentication, Safari and WebKit》
The ability to distribute video
以低比特率分散
with Alpha at low bitrates opens
带有 Alpha 的视频
opportunities for authoring apps
这种能力为创作 App 提供了机会
to provide background removal.
以提供背景删除
Here I am in front of a green
现在我站在一张
sheet hung from the wall
挂在墙上的绿色幕布前
recorded using an iPhone.
这是用 iPhone 录制的
I wish I was here.
我希望我在这里
I used a custom video compositor
我使用了一个自定义的视频合成器
with a co-image filter to
和一个共同图像过滤器
replace the green pixels with
用透明来替换绿色像素
transparency and exported it to
并将其导出到一个
a video with Alpha.
带 Alpha 的影片当中
I wish I was here.
我希望我在这里
And now I can overlay this video
现在我可以
on any background I like.
在我喜欢的任何背景上
I wish I was here.
叠加这个视频
We are providing sample code
我们将提供示例代码
showing how to do this and write
显示了如何执行此操作
the resulting HEVC video with
并使用 Alpha 影片编写生成的
Alpha movie.
HEVC 视频
So how does this work?
那么这是如何工作的呢
As you know, movie files contain
如你所知影片文件
tracks of various media types.
包含各种媒体类型的曲目
A video track contains video
视频轨道包含视频帧
HEVC video with Alpha is
带有 Alpha 的
contained inside a single video
HEVC 视频包含在
track in the movie.
影片的单个视频轨道内
In the single track, each frame
在单轨中
contains 2 parts called layers
每个帧包含两个称为层的部分
and each layer is compressed
每个层使用 HEVC 编解码器
using the HEVC codec.
进行压缩
The base layer contains the
底层像往常一样
colored image of the frame as
包含帧的彩色图像
The Alpha layer contains just
Alpha 图层仅包含
the Alpha channel of the frame.
帧的 Alpha 通道
This is done using special HEVC
这是使用特殊的
syntax which identifies the 2
HEVC 语法来完成的
layers.
能识别出这两个层级
The HEVC rules for this syntax
该语法的 HEVC 规则
mean that the HEVC decoder that
意味着
does not know how to handle the
不知道如何处理
Alpha layer will ignore it and
Alpha 层的 HEVC 解码器
display the base layer alone.
将忽略它并仅显示基本层
Let's move along and talk about
我们来继续讨论
how to use it.
如何使用它
HEVC with Alpha encoding is
具有 Alpha 编码的 HEVC
integrated into numerous AV
被集成到众多
Foundation APIs.
AVFoundation API 中
Let's look at content creation,
例如
for example.
我们看看内容创建
You can render video frames with
你可以在 App 中
Alpha in your application and
使用 Alpha 渲染视频帧
use AVAssetWriter to encode them
并使用 AVAssetWriter 进行编码
and write them to a movie file.
并将其写入影片文件
You can use new presets
你可以使用
available with
AVAssetExportSession
AVAssetExportSession to
提供的新预设
transcode video formats
将包含 Alpha
containing Alpha including Apple
包括 Apple ProRes 4444 的视频格式
ProRes 4444 into HEVC with
转码为带 Alpha 的 HEVC
These new HEVC presets have the
这些新的 HEVC 预设
suffix with Alpha.
带有 WithAlpha 的后缀
You can also use
你还可以使用
AVAssettExportSession to burn
AVAssettExportSession
in a specific background color
以特定的背景色刻录
converting a movie with Alpha
将具有 Alpha 的影片
into a movie without Alpha, that
转换为不带 Alpha 的影片
will play on players that don't
该影片将在不支持带有 Alpha 的
support HEVC with Alpha.
播放器上播放
Or you can also use the HEVC
或者你也可以
with Alpha video encoder
通过 VTCompressionSession
directly via
将 HEVC 与 Alpha
VTCompressionSession.
视频编码器配合使用
Looking at AVFoundation's
我们来看看 AVFoundation 的回放 API
is supported by AVPlayer and
AVPlayer 和 AVPlayerLayer 支持带有 Alpha 的 HEVC
AVPlayerLayer for display in
通过 Core Animation AppKit 和 UIKit
your apps view hierarchy via
显示在 App 视图层次结构中
The video in AVPlayerLayer will
AvPlayerLayer 中的视频
be displayed with a transparent
将以透明背景显示
background and composed with the
并与其他层和视图融为一体
Alternatively you can access a
或者你可以使用
sequence of decoded video frames
AVPlayerItemVideoOutput
directly using
直接访问一系列
AVPlayerItemVideoOutput.
已解码的视频帧
This is a great choice when you
当你想要将这些视频帧
want to incorporate those video
合并到使用 Metal SpriteKit
frames into a custom rendering
和其他基于 GPU 的
you're doing using Metal,
渲染 API 的自定义渲染中时
SpriteKit and other GPU-based
这是个很好的选择
If you need to decode frames for
如果你需要
another purpose, you can use
为其他目的而解码帧
AVAssetImageGenerator directory
可以直接使用 AVAssetImageGenerator
and individual frame of the
和影片的单个帧
movie as a CGImage with Alpha.
作为带 Alpha 的 CGImage
You can use AVAssetReader to
你可以使用 AVAssetReader
extract video frames for use in
提取视频帧以用于
a non-playback workflow.
非回放工作流
You can also use the HEVC with
你也可以直接通过 VTDecompressionSession
Alpha video decoder directly via
将 HEVC 与 Alpha 视频解码器配合使用
VTDecompressionSession.
视频解码器配合使用
In short because HEVC with Alpha
简而言之
is integrated into AVFoundation
因为带有 Alpha 的 HEVC
at the level of a video codec,
在视频编解码器的级别
it fits in well into all these
集成到了 AVFoundation 中
familiar API workflows.
所以以它很适合所有熟悉的 API 工作流
Now let us see how we can
现在让我们看看
accomplish this in code.
如何在代码中实现这一点
When encoding a movie, when
对影片进行编码时
configuring your AVAssetWriter
在配置 AVAssetWriter 输入
input or VTCompressionSession,
或 VTCompressionSession 时
use the video codec type HEVC
使用带 Alpha 的
with Alpha.
视频编解码器类型 HEVC
This is a special signal that
这是 Alpha 通道
the Alpha channel should be
应编码的特殊信号
The encoded file will have the
编码文件将具有
standard HEVC codec type.
标准 HEVC 编解码器类型
It will be backwards compatible.
它将向后兼容
An HEVC player that does not
不能读出 Alpha 的
understand Alpha will display
HEVC 播放器
only the base video layer.
将只显示基本视频层
It will ignore the Alpha
它将忽略 Alpha 部分
If you work with Alpha channels,
如果使用 Alpha 通道
you may know that there are 2
你可能会明白
strategies for how to write
有两种方法
video data to a file,
可以将视频数据写入文件
premultiplied Alpha or straight
Premultiplied Alpha
Alpha, also known as
Straight Alpha
unassociated Alpha or
后者也被称为 Unassociated Alpha
non-premultiplied Alpha.
或 Non-premultiplied Alpha
The tradeoffs between these
这些选择之间的权衡
choices are beyond the scope of
超出了本次讨论的范围
If you're familiar with these,
如果你熟悉这些
what you need to know is that
你要知道的是
both are supported.
两者都能被支持
If you're not similar with
假如与这些不相似
these, we recommend the default,
我们建议使用默认值
which is premultiplied Alpha.
即 Premultiplied Alpha
It's the natural choice in most
它是大多数基于 GPU 的
GPU-based rendering parts and it
渲染部件的自然选择
scales better.
并且具有更好的伸缩性
Now looking at the code, you may
现在查看代码
specify the Alpha mode by either
你可以通过
configuring the compression
配置压缩会话
session or as a buffer
或作为缓冲附件
attachment.
来指定 Alpha 模式
As a safety mechanism if the
作为一种安全机制
setting and the buffer
如果设置和缓冲区附件
attachment are both specified
都被指定并且
and they do not match, the
它们不匹配败
encoding operation will fail.
编码操作将失败
Our APIs require the
我们的 API
Alpha channel to be encoded with
要求 Alpha 通道
fixed quality because video
以固定的质量进行编码
encoding artifacts in the Alpha
因为 Alpha 通道中的
channel can be bothersome in
视频编码失真可能很麻烦
ways that the same artifacts
因为相同的失真
wouldn't be in the base layer.
不会出现在基础层中
Our APIs let you
如果需要 我们的 API
control the base layers bitrate
可让你分别控制
and the Alpha channel's quality
基本层比特率
separately if you need to.
和 Alpha 通道的质量
Now, looking at the code you can
现在我们来看看代码
specify the Alpha layer quality
你可以使用
using target quality for Alpha
Alpha 参数的目标质量
parameter.
指定 Alpha 图层质量
It is arranged between 0 and 1
它的区间在 0 和 1 之间
where 1 means it is close to
其中 1 表示它接近无损
The bitrate parameter you
指定的比特率参数
specify only applies to the base
仅适用于基础层
layer and is ignored by the
Alpha 图层将忽略该参数
To detect the presence of an
要检测 Alpha 通道的存在
Alpha channel, you can either
可以用 withMediaCharacteristic:.containsAlphaChannel
can query the format description
也可以查询
extension contains Alpha
formatDescription.extensions[.containsAlphaChannel]
If you are trying to export HEVC
如果你试图
with Alpha movie, use to
用 Alpha 影片导出 HEVC
determine compatibility API to
请使用 determineCompatibility API
validate that Alpha is present
以验证源资源中
in the source asset.
是否存在 Alpha
This validation only takes the
此验证只考虑源影片
source movie into account not
而不考虑视频合成
So you must skip it if you are
因此如果使用视频合成
using a video composition to
从没有 Alpha 通道的源
generate a new Alpha channel
生成新的 Alpha 通道
from sources that do not have
则必须跳过它
There are a lot of video players
当前生态中有很多
in the ecosystem.
视频播放器
Many of them don't support HEVC
不支持 HEVC
let alone HEVC with Alpha.
更不用说带 Alpha 通道的 HEVC 了
You can remove the Alpha channel
可以通过以纯色背景颜色
by burning in a solid background
进行刻录来移除
color.
Alpha 通道
We have added some convenience
我们添加了一些方便的 API
API and sample code to help
和示例代码
simplify this conversion.
来帮助简化这种转换
If you're looking to build
如果你希望
support into a non-Apple media
在非 Apple 媒体框架中
framework, we have published a
构建支持
specification for an
我们已经发布了
interoperability profile that
应该阅读的互操作性配置文件的规范
you should read, but if you
你们应该阅读一下
can't wait, here is a sneak
但是如果你等不及了
peek.
这里可以先睹为快
To summarize, HEVC video with
总而言之带有 Alpha 的
Alpha is a cool new feature.
HEVC 视频是一个很酷的新功能
It takes advantage of HEVC's
它利用了 HEVC
state of the art compression
最先进的压缩技术
It is supported on iOS 13, tvOS
iOS 13 tvOS 13
13 and macOS Catalina.
和 macOS Catalina 都支持它
It takes advantage of hardware
它利用了最近
acceleration on recent devices.
设备上的硬件加速
It is well integrated into
它很好地集成到 AVFoundation 中
AVFoundation for use in your apps.
可以在你的 App 中使用
It is also integrated in Safari
它还集成在 Safari 中
for use in your web experiences.
用于你的 Web 体验
HEVC with Alpha brings us new
带有 Alpha 的 HEVC
opportunities for creative
为开发人员和用户
expression for both developers
带来了新的
and users alike.
有创造性的表达机会
We can't wait to see the ways
我们已经迫不及待地
you can take advantage of it in
想看看你在 App 中
your apps.
如何利用它
Thank you for your time.
感谢大家